# Xavier Rodriguez

xavier.bng.rgz@gmail.com.com | ■ (206)582-8330

🕠 https://xavirb.github.io/ | 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/xavier-rodriguez-a9120023b/

# Software Engineer

With a background in software development and analysis from Kent, Washington, I've consistently demonstrated my adaptability and collaboration skills in diverse teams. Bringing a blend of technical expertise, analytical proficiency, and a positive can-do attitude. I am passionate about using my experience to drive solutions.

## Skills

Languages **Software & Tools** HTML5/CSS

React.is JavaScript **Database Technologies** iQuery

C++ Geojson GitHub PHP API's Visual Studios Python MySQL Rash Node.js **Firebase** PowerShell

**MATLAB** Command Prompt Racket

## **Design & Problem Solving:**

Ability to creatively design systems, components, and processes.

#### Education

Western Washington University, Bellingham, WA

Graduated Fall 2023

B.S. in Mathematics Computer Science, Minor: Leadership

Relevant Coursework:

**Mathematical and Optimization** 

Numerical Computation Analysis of Algorithms **Linear Optimization** 

Numerical Linear Algebra

**Data Structures and Systems** 

Linear Data Structures **Data Structures** Computer Systems I

**Programming and Design** Computer Programming

Object Oriented Design

Security Cyber Defense

# **Projects**

#### Autism Strength Website, Lead Dev, Research

September 2022 - present

#### Bellingham, WA

React.js, CSS, Babel, JavaScript, Redux, node.js, Firebase

- · Working with a professor at Western Washington University creating a full stack website for students with autism.
- · Developing a networking platform to connect students with autism, fostering mentor-mentee relationships within the community.
- · Used the various different languages and frameworks such as; Reat.js, CSS, Babel, JavaScript, Redux, node.js and **Firebase**
- Created a matching algorithm that matches the mentor with the mentee based on interests.
- · Ensured timely project completion by creating strategic plan, meeting key deadlines, and coordinating with supervising professor and peers.
- Communicated research findings to both technical and non-technical audiences

Phicore.com, Client August 2022

## Bellingham, WA

HTML5/CSS, JavaScript, PHP, jQuery, sass

- Developed and designed the website for my client.
- · Created a booking system for the website using JavaScript and PHP.
- Guaranteed website compatibility with mobile devices across any screen size.
- Ensured timely project completion by creating strategic plan, and coordinating with client.

## Manhattan Traffic, Personal project

May 2022

#### HTML, Geojson, Leaflet API

- Demonstrated my ability to show the live traffic data of New York Manhattan using NYC real-time traffic data via API.
- Used longitude and latitude coordinates to break Manhattan into parts indicating where heavy flow of traffic exists.
- Strengthened my skills in HTML, Geojson and, Leaflet API as these were used to create the project.

#### Python

- Wrote code in python to show a finite number of triangles recursively.
- Implemented mathematical formulas in the python code.
- · Expanded my knowledge of different concepts such as using a canvas in python and using a canvas library.

## Work Experience

#### Web Developer, Western Washington University

Aug 2022-Present

#### Bellingham, WA

- Worked at the Sustainability Engagement Institute as a Web Developer and a communications assistant.
- Used Drupal and JavaScript to implement website designs and functionality's.
- Gained skills on Server-Side Development (specifically PHP/MySQL).
- Cultivated and displayed creative artistic and graphic design.
- · Regularly reviewed and updated SEI website to maximize content accuracy and accessibility.
- Gained project management skills, including the ability to work on multiple projects simultaneously.
- Presented web and graphic design concepts to clients and advise clients on strategies to reach a particular audience.
- · Gained Knowledge in Adobe Suite and Creative Cloud.

### **Dominos, Delivery Expert**

June 2021-Present

#### Bellingham, WA

- Gained experience in the distribution to retail logistics process.
- · Built relationships with dispatchers and contractors to ensure project and operational efficiency.
- Developed an inventory tracking solution that minimized outdated products by 70% by implementing a labelling process and FIFO methods on every product.
- Ensured project and operational efficiency by working with tracking software and OTD systems.
- · Trained drivers on franchise delivery software during rollout.

## Target, GSA (Front end supervisor)

Sept 2018-2021

#### Bellingham, WA

- · Worked with customers at guest service during the busiest hours of the day.
- Assigned lunches and breaks for my coworkers.
- Trained current and new employees at guest service and was fluent with the online system.
- Worked closely with the logistics teams on outbound and inbound shipments.
- Used delivery and order dispatching systems to analyze, finalize and process orders from distribution centers across the country.
- Increased sale's metrics by 4% in the 2018 Calendar year by ensuring reverse logistics and order operational systems were up to date by manually updating POS and outbound tracking systems.
- Used active inventory (AS) systems to update and keep track of allocated inventory and sold directories.